{
  "reference_number": "10671",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "New Zealand has a unique position being known as 'clean', 'green', 'pure' with out beautiful forestry, scenery, lakes, rivers and\n mountains. In 1987 New Zealand implemented the New Zealand Nuclear Free Zone, Disarmament, and Arms Control Act. We should\n\n triple down on those sentiments. Do everything we can to build a zero emissions, zero nuclear, 100% renewable 'circular society' for\n our health and future, our children's future, New Zealand as a desirable place to live and visit and Earth. To me it makes sense for\n\n New Zealand to strive to be a world leader in green energy. That is the type of country I want to live in."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Carbon tax? It could be beneficial if a carbon tax was implemented which steadily increased each year, that increase being known\n years in advance. This would allow individuals to see clear financial benefits to making cleaner investments (EV, solar panels, local\n produce). Appropriate marketing for citizens explaining the 'why' of the tax. A benefit would be if it was easy for a citizen to easily track\n\n and see the tax being spent 100% toward renewable generation / carbon reduction. The ultimate goal for this tax would not to be\n sustainable but to keep increasing but constantly see less in total collections (clean (untaxed) tech incentivized). This is not my area\n\n of expertise."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "If I can read through the 'Our Climate Your Say' document before Thursday I'll make another submission. Cheers.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
